(Sheldon:)In the pre-Christian era, as the winter
solstice approached and the plants died...
...pagans brought evergreen boughs in their
homes as an act of sympathetic magic...
(Sheldon:)...intended to guard the life essences
of the plants until spring.
This custom was appropriated
by northern Europeans...
(Sheldon:)...and, eventually, it becomes
the so-called Christmas tree.
(Howard:)And that, Charlie Brown,
is what boredom is all about.
(Penny:)Okay, well, thank you for that.
I got you and Leonard silly neighbor gifts...
(Penny:)- ...so I'll just put them under my tree.
- Wait.
(Sheldon:)- You bought me a present?
- Uh-huh.
(Sheldon:)Why would you do such a thing?
- I don't know. Because it's Christmas?
- Oh, Penny.
(Sheldon:)I know you think you're being generous...
(Sheldon:)...but the foundation of gift-giving
is reciprocity.
(Sheldon:)You haven't given me a gift,
you've given me an obligation.
(Howard:)Don't feel bad, Penny.
It's a classic rookie mistake.
(Howard:)My first Hanukkah with Sheldon,
he yelled at me for eight nights.
(Penny:)It's okay.
You don't have to get me anything.